y I promise
you this is going to be
where
where okay fat check number nine
Adventist believe that Satan is their
sin Bearer let's listen to
Elsie in with the investigative
judgment so they believe that when
Christ would have finish his
intercessory work in heaven he's going
to be turning and at that time now he's
going to cease interceding for Adventist
so they have to stand before God without
a mediator while he's on his way and
they would have to have been sin the
perfect then and so when he comes he's
actually going to take all of the sins
of God's people that Satan would have
caused them to commit and then he places
them on Satan who is going to Bear them
and so let me read a quote from her
where she says exactly this and what
they do after this now is just rework it
in scripture so they go to Leviticus
chapter 16 and they say see one go is
for the Lord that was killed and
sacrificed the other goat that bears the
sins away as AEL it is Satan so Satan is
the scapegoat he is the sin Bearer so
let me read
okay all right so I want you to note
what happens here I want you to note
that those last words so Satan is the
sin Bearer that's a very
manipulative
statement now let me say this I can most
people have have never even heard of a
scapegoat right so it's it's amazing to
me how you're speaking to an
audience pretending to assume that oh
everybody has read Leviticus 16 and
knows about the scapegoat and we all
know that the scapegoat is Jesus that's
a
no-brainer it's again taking advantage
of your
ignorance and so so when you say oh and
so they believe that Satan is their sin
Bearer
whoa y'all believe what Satan is your
sin Bearer
yeah y'all are off and I understand that
because that sounds crazy right Satan is
your sin Bearer that is
crazy let's see do Adventist believe
that Satan is our sin Bearer let's go to
the
screen we cannot find Salvation in our
own individual selves we ought to look
unto Jesus who is the author and
finisher of our faith and as we look we
live how hard poor mortal strives how
hard poor Mortals strive to be sin
bearers for themselves and for others
but the only sin Bearer is Jesus Christ
huh the only sin Bearer is Jesus Christ
how about this one in ours when we Cloud
when in hours when clouds Encompass the
soul Christ is not far from every one of
us to whom shall we go if not to the sin
Bearer The Great healer of human woe
listen to me
y'all Adventists do not believe that
Satan is our sin Bearer but that's what
Preston walked away with
right he genuinely walked away with oh
Adventists think that Satan is their sin
Bearer and yes if that were true that
would be crazy yes so so ex Adventist
let me say this the reason I'm quoting
Ellen White and and I want you to
understand this you know
honestly the reason I'm quoting Ellen
White is because the entire presentation
the entire response right was not about
Bible when I quoted Bible did a whole
response on the scapegoat about the
using the
Bible their response to my video and to
all the other adl's video and the
various other Ministries that all
responded using Bible their response was
to just talk about Ellen White and say
Ellen White taught this Ellen White
believed this chur they get this from
Ellen White so what am I to do right
right to show that to show that what
you're saying not not what you're saying
but what they're saying is not true it's
fat that's why we we're calling this 15
fat checks and that Ellen White didn't
believe that and that's not
where right
so when when you come with scripture
we're going to respond with scripture
so ex Adventist just just as a as a note
to because I saw your comment in the
chat and uh I'm glad you're here by the
way I'm glad you're here all right so
once again let's go to the screen this
is false now we're going to really get
into the scapegoat and then we are going
to be almost there you all almost there
because these next ones are going to
this is
my this is the one fat check 10 SD are
alone in believing Satan is the
scapegoat let's check out what Elsie has
to say this for the Lord that was killed
and sacrificed the other goat that bears
the sins away as AEL it is Satan so
Satan is the scapegoat he is the sin
Bearer so let me read a quote uh from
her and of course they they adhere to a
lot of the Jewish folk law and myth
around Azazel in the ancient naries
period and some reformers who would have
made statements along that line to try
to justify it but if you notice today
though as Scholars Christian Scholars
continue to study you would not find any
Christian Church that holds to Satan
being the scapegoat when they
understand uh the typology in Leviticus
chapter 16 and then what scripture says
in Isaiah 53 Peter and many other places
about Jesus and the whole process of
atonement the day of atonement
one okay
so here here is the amazing thing about
this I don't know if you saw what what
just
happened he basically just said if you
go back to the early church and the
reformers and you know certain certain
people you will see that people in
Christianity have held that Azazel is
Satan
but now watch what he said now but since
Scholars got smarter now they understand
the typology and now you find nobody
teaching that the scapegoat is Satan
really how does that
work so the church back then or people
back then wouldn't have known about
Isaiah 53 they wouldn't have known about
these other verses and so they would
have just erroneously concluded that the
scapegoat is Satan so so let let's watch
this let's go to the screen and y'all
get ready we're almost there you guys
y'all get ready and just watch okay
let's go to the
screen here is arenus in his work
against heresies we a lot of Christians
love to quote the church fathers the
church fathers the church fathers listen
to what irania said which Satan thy true
father enables thee still to accomplish
by means of Azazel that fallen and yet
mighty
Angel did ananus think that Satan was
his sin
Bearer how about
origin here is origin again celsus
here's what he says for the serpent
having become the cause of man's
expulsion from the Divine Paradise
obscurely Shadows forth something
similar moreover the goat which in The
Book of Leviticus is sent away Into the
Wilderness and which in the Hebrew
language is named Azazel
was none other than this speaking of the
serpent
M
Satan did origin believe that Satan was
his sin Bearer or did he see in the
symbol of the scapegoat something that
represented the taking away of sin not
the bearing of sin to forgive us we all
know that's Jesus's work
right it is it is an it is it is
absolute error to give the impression
that Adventists like we pray to Satan oh
you know forgive us of our
sin come on let's keep going here is
origin again for he does not intercede
well listen y'all the day of atonement
remains for us until the sun sets origin
thought the day of atonement was yet
future and wouldn't be fulfilled till
the very end of time he says the day of
atonement for us uh for us remains until
the sun sets that is until the world
comes to an end for let us stand before
the gates waiting for our high priest
who remains within the holy of holies
that is before the father and who
intercedes not for the sins of everyone
but for the sins of those who wait for
him for he does not intercede for those
who come into the lot of the he goat
which is sent into the Wilderness he
intercedes only for those who are of the
lot of the Lord wow is origin was origin
part of a
cult was origin crazy was origin not
following the Bible did origin read the
writings of Ellen White to come to this
conclusion that the scapegoat was a
symbol for those who were not saved
right here is lexam Bible dictionary
let's go back to the screen lexam Bible
dictionary lexam Bible dictionary
as AEL unclear designation in Leviticus
168 10 and 26 related to the scapegoat
ceremony on the day of atonement
multiple theories exist regarding its
meaning let me just stop right here
y'all let me just stop right here
because what what Elsie and Mason did
was they presented this idea that there
is only one view of the scapegoat and
everybody knows that the scapegoat
represents Jesus and those Adventists
are crazy because they're the only ones
that believe that the scap goat
represents something other than Jesus
here in the lexum Bible dictionary which
is not an Adventist dictionary you guys
they say multiple theories exist
regarding its meaning and they weren't
writing that because they were thinking
of Adventist
right let me
demonstrate here is erman's Bible
dictionary erman's Bible dictionary
again
not a bi not a not an Adventist Bible
dictionary but note what it says some
commentators consider Azazel a kind of
desert demon perhaps one of the satires
Leviticus 16 does not state that this
goat is an offering to such a demon
rather the animal is an insult to it
Laden as it as it is with Israel's sin
actually human sin now belongs to the
demon
this is the erman's Bible
dictionary why are they saying some
commentators listen
y'all your ignorance can be taken
advantage of and that's what's happening
here because they're coming across like
huh can you imagine the craziness of
actually believing that the scapegoat
would be a symbol of Satan and yet here
we have commentators who agree that the
scapegoat is a symbol of Satan and yet
none of those commentators would ever
open their mouth and perch their lips to
say something like we believe Satan is
our sin Bearer and Satan died for the
sins of the world come on you
guys let's be honest let's not take
advantage of people's ignorance because
they're not looking at edan's Bible
erman's Bible dictionary the average
person is not looking at this the
average person is not looking up what
Scholars are having to say no they're
just trusting and this is why I say it
over and over again
y'all do not put your trust in the arm
of
Flesh don't do it right trust the word
of God study to show
yourself approved let's go back to the
screen let's go back to the screen in
Lex him's Bible dictionary they actually
list out the four options that people
have when it comes to Azazel some
believe Azazel is a name of a demon some
believe it's a location some believe
it's an abstract noun some believe it's
a compound word I'm not trying to tell
you right now hey believe what we say
I'm just simply saying if there are
different views being held by different
people out there why are you calling
Adventist a cult and acting like we are
the only one that have this really crazy
off-the-wall
View and if y'all are studying as you
claim that you are as Scholars you
should know that this view is a view
that is not only held by
Adventists let's go back to the screen
anchors Bible commentary series as far
as I know not an Adventist Bible
commentary right here's what they say
the most plausible explanation is that
El is the name of a demon who has been
eviscerated of his Earth while demonic
Powers by Priestly legislators first the
goat sent him is not an offering it is
not treated as a sacrifice it doesn't
die there's no shedding of blood for the
remission of sins requiring Slaughter
blood manipulation and the like nor does
it have the effect of a sacrifice namely
propitiation and experation and so on
moreover an anal animal Laden with
impurities would not be acceptable as an
offering either to God or to a demon
second the goat is not the vicarious
substitute for Israel because there is
no indication that it was punished put
to death or demonically attacked in
Israel's place instead of being an
offering or substitute the goat is
simply the vehicle to dispatch Israel's
impurities and sins to the Wilderness or
the
Netherworld the banishment of evil to an
inaccessible place is a form of
elimination amply attested in ancient
near East you guys let's come back to
the
screen everything I am reading to
you I'm not I'm not even arguing right
now about whether the position is right
or
wrong why because we can't even get to
that point because we got to spend
almost two hours correcting what we
believe right you guys we don't believe
that you guys know other people believe
this too are you calling them a cult are
you going to tell people don't buy the
anchor Bible
series this is mainstream Christianity
mainstream mainstream Christianity are
you going to tell people stay away from
the anchor Bible
series here's another one we're almost
done y'all we're almost there
we have only one view remaining namely
that which regards Azazel as a
description of a personal being an evil
demon and this is from the book uh
written by John Henrik CTS and a
Lutheran
[Laughter]
Theologian are Lutheran a cult y'all are
Lutheran a cult I'm sorry I'm just
getting too excited are Lutheran a cult
please help me out
help me
out help me to understand here is a
Lutheran scholar who is writing that
Azazel is a
demon
okay y'all get my slides you want my
slides you will get them here is Kyle
and D's commentary a Lutheran commentary
and let me read to you what they have to
say by both goats Israel was delivered
from all sins and transgressions but by
the one which was upon which the lot for
Jehovah fell it was so with regard to
Jehovah by the other upon which the lot
fell for Azazel was regard to
Azazel Israel I'm going to read the
highlighted part but Israel had also
been brought by its sin into a distinct
relationship to Azazel the head of the
evil spirits and it was necessary that
this should be brought to an end if
reconciliation with God was to be
perfectly secure you guys do you know
how many how many do you know that kale
this is a Lutheran commentary you
guys yeah what do you do with
this what do you do with this okay I'm
skipping